<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubewarden: Kubernetes Dynamic Admission at your fingertips on Kubewarden</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Kubewarden: Kubernetes Dynamic Admission at your fingertips on Kubewarden</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 13:28:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scanning secrets in environment variables</title><link>/blog/2022/10/env-var-secrets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/10/env-var-secrets/</guid><description>We are thrilled to announce you can now scan your environment variables for secrets with the new env-variable-secrets-scanner-policy! This policy rejects a Pod or workload resources such as Deployments, ReplicaSets, DaemonSets , ReplicationControllers, Jobs, CronJobs etc. if a secret is found in the environment variable within a container, init container, or ephemeral container. Secrets that are leaked in plain text or in base64 encoded variables are detected.
This policy uses rusty hog, an open source secret scanner from New Relic.</description></item><item><title>v1.1.1 is out 🎉</title><link>/blog/2022/07/v1.1.1-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/07/v1.1.1-release/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the first minor release of v1.0: v1.1.1 is now available!
Apart from being a nice looking number, v1.1.1 includes:
Improved the policies API for Sigstore verification by adding new backwards-compatible WaPC host callback v2/verify functions to the API. Check them out here to add support for your language of choice.
This has been used in the verify-image-signatures policy to simplify verification of GitHub Actions signatures and others.</description></item><item><title>Kubewarden policies, now on Artifact Hub!</title><link>/blog/2022/07/artifact-hub-supports-kubewarden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/07/artifact-hub-supports-kubewarden/</guid><description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce that Artifact Hub now supports Kubewarden policies! 🤯 🥳
Artifact Hub is the de-facto place where Cloud Native users search for helm charts, container images, and other kinds of artifacts and configurations of different CNCF projects. That&amp;rsquo;s why we are super excited and honored to have Kubewarden policies listed on Artifact Hub.
This would not have been possible without the work done by the Artifact Hub team.</description></item><item><title>Verify image signatures with GitHub Actions and KeylessPrefix</title><link>/blog/2022/07/verify-signatures-with-gha-and-prefix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/07/verify-signatures-with-gha-and-prefix/</guid><description>With the latest releases of Kubewarden v1.1.0 and the verify-image-signatures policy, it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to use GithubActions or KeylessPrefix for verifying images. Read our previous blog post if you want to learn more about how to verify container images with Sigstore using Kubewarden.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see it in action! We want to verify the image ghcr.io/raulcabello/app-example which was built and signed inside a GitHub action using this GitHub Action.
Out of the box, GitHub Actions have a specially crafted environment that makes Sigstore keyless signing work in a non-interactive way.</description></item><item><title>Migrate your PSPs to Kubewarden policies!</title><link>/blog/2022/07/psp-migration-script/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/07/psp-migration-script/</guid><description>As announced in past blog posts, Kubewarden has 100% coverage of the deprecated, and soon to be removed, Kubernetes PSPs. If everything goes as expected the PSPs will be removed in Kubernetes v1.25 due for release on 23rd August 2022.
The Kubewarden team has written a script that leverages the migration tool written by AppVia, to migrate PSP automatically. The tool is capable of reading PSPs YAML and can generate the equivalent policies in many different policy engines.</description></item><item><title>Kubewarden reaches 1.0.0 release 🎉</title><link>/blog/2022/06/v1-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/06/v1-release/</guid><description>Kubewarden is a policy engine for Kubernetes that is part of CNCF Sandbox.
Never heard of Kubewarden before? Do you want to know what makes Kubewarden stand out among similar solutions? This is a high level overview of Kubewarden&amp;rsquo;s unique points:
Boost Policy Authors' productivity: write policies using your favorite programming language. Leverage your knowledge, skills and tools. Policies are portable WebAssembly modules Reuse your existing Open Policy Agent / Gatekeeper policies Distribute policies using regular container registries Secure supply chain, leverage Sigstore to sign and verify policies Today, a year and a half since its conception, we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce the release of Kubewarden v1.</description></item><item><title>CNCF Sandbox admission 🎊</title><link>/blog/2022/06/cncf-sandbox-inclusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/06/cncf-sandbox-inclusion/</guid><description>Today the whole Kubewarden team is overjoyed because the Kubewarden project has just been accepted into the CNCF Sandbox!!! 🥳
This is a great achievement for the whole team and is the beginning of our journey into CNCF. Also, many thanks to the CNCF TOC for the feedback they provided during the project evaluation.
What&amp;rsquo;s next? The admission happens at an interesting time since we are currently testing the 1.0.0-rc1 release of Kubewarden.</description></item><item><title>Secure Supply Chain: Verifying image signatures</title><link>/blog/2022/05/verifying-image-signatures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/verifying-image-signatures/</guid><description>After these last releases Kubewarden now has support for verifying the integrity and authenticity of artifacts within Kubewarden using the Sigstore project. In this post, we shall focus on verifying container image signatures using the new verify-image-signatures policy.
To learn more about how Sigstore works, take a look at our previous post
Verify Image Signatures Policy This policy validates Pods by checking their container images for signatures (that is, containers, init containers and ephemeral containers in the pod)</description></item><item><title>Have you migrated your Kubernetes PodSecurityPolicy?</title><link>/blog/2022/05/psp-migration-docs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/psp-migration-docs/</guid><description>If you use a version of Kubernetes (&amp;lt; v1.24) that supports the deprecated PodSecurityPolicy (a.k.a PSP), you would be wondering what to do after the Kubernetes v1.25 version when the PSP will be removed. With this in mind, the Kuberwarden team wrote a documentation to help users migrate away from PSPs to Kuberwarden policies.
As you know, the original Pod Security Policies had many configuration knobs. The Kubewarden team created a series of policies that offer a 100% feature parity with all the soon to be dropped Pod Security Policies.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Monitor mode</title><link>/blog/2022/05/monitor-mode/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/monitor-mode/</guid><description>Policies are a core component of a Kubernetes cluster story that involves security, compliance and consistency.
Being this process an iterative one, it&amp;rsquo;s common for new policies to potentially reject operations that we might be issuing today in our production clusters.
As an example, we might have decided that it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to change certain annotations on existing resources after the fact. In this case, we don&amp;rsquo;t want to revoke UPDATE rights completely, but just to define an inalterable set of annotations after the resource has been created.</description></item><item><title>Secure Supply Chain with Kubewarden: securing Kubewarden policies</title><link>/blog/2022/04/securing-kubewarden-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/04/securing-kubewarden-policies/</guid><description>With recent releases, the Kubewarden stack supports verifying the integrity and authenticity of content using the Sigstore project.
In this post, we focus on Kubewarden Policies and how to create a Secure Supply Chain for them.
Sigstore? Since a full Sigstore dive is not within the scope for this post, we recommend checking out their nice docs.
In short, Sigstore provides an automatable workflow to match the distributed Open Source development model.</description></item><item><title>CRI-O CVE-2022-0811 Mitigation</title><link>/blog/2022/03/cri-o-cve-mitigation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/03/cri-o-cve-mitigation/</guid><description>Recently a severe CVE in the CRI-O container engine come to public. The flaw in CRI-O allows bad actors to gain root access and run arbitrary code in the host machine.
A fix for the issue is already available and you should update your cluster to avoid any headache in the future. But if you cannot do that right away, use Kubewarden to mitigate the impact of this issue. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to prevent pods with sysctl configuration to run in the cluster with the policy sysctl-psp available in the Policy Hub.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the AdmissionPolicy</title><link>/blog/2022/03/admission-policy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/03/admission-policy/</guid><description>Up till now, the only way to define a policy in Kubewarden was to use the ClusterAdmissionPolicy resource that would be applied to cluster-wide resources across all namespaces.
That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce the new AdmissionPolicy resource. This new resource is created inside a namespace and the policies will only process the requests that are targeting the namespace where the AdmissionPolicy is defined. Except from being a &amp;ldquo;namespaced&amp;rdquo; resource, AdmissionPolicy works exactly the same as the ClusterAdmissionPolicy.</description></item><item><title>Multiplatform Kubewarden</title><link>/blog/2022/02/multiplatform-kubewarden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/02/multiplatform-kubewarden/</guid><description>The Kubewarden team is glad to announce that in the spirit of helping Policy Authors and Cluster Administrators, the project is now officially multiplatform.
The list of supported platforms as of now are:
Policy Server, as a container image:
linux/amd64 (with the musl libc) linux/arm64 (with the musl libc) kwctl, as a standalone binary:
darwin (x86_64) linux (aarch64, with the musl libc) linux (x86_64, with the musl libc) windows (x86_64, with MSVC) We have prioritized the usage of the same dependencies and toolchain on platforms where we were able to do so.</description></item><item><title>Kubewarden policies cover all the Kubernetes Pod Security Policies</title><link>/blog/2022/01/mutating-policy-behave-as-validating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/01/mutating-policy-behave-as-validating/</guid><description>The Kubewarden team worked tirelessly to create equivalent Kubewarden policies for all the deprecated Pod Security Policies (PSP). In order to reach this very important milestone, the team wrote the policies with the same validations available in the Kubernetes PSPs, and we counted on the community help to map and validate the policies.
This will allow our users to replace deprecated PSPs while continuing to enforce their security rules.
The Kubewarden policies which replace all the Kubernetes PSPs, are available in the Policy Hub, and you can find them by typing the keyword &amp;ldquo;PSP&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Policy Server on aarch64</title><link>/blog/2022/01/policy-server-on-aarch64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/01/policy-server-on-aarch64/</guid><description>We recently got notified that the policy-server was crashing in an aarch64 environment. The moment in which it got a request from the API server, it crashed immediately with a SIGSEGV signal.
We figured out that this was only happening when the request was a TLS one, and that the problem was related to the OpenSSL stack and the way we were producing the final image of the policy-server with the OpenSSL stack.</description></item><item><title>First year of Kubewarden</title><link>/blog/2021/12/first-year-of-kubewarden/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/12/first-year-of-kubewarden/</guid><description>Year 2021 is almost over. Let&amp;rsquo;s take that as a chance to look back at what has been achieved during the 1st year of life of the Kubewarden project.
Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll also talk about what we plan to do during the next one.
2021 Highlights Project Announcement The Kubewarden project has been introduced to the masses for the 1st time during KubeCon Europe 2021. During this presentation, Rafael and I explained what lead us to rethink how Kubernetes policies could be written and distributed.</description></item><item><title>Deep Dive into policy logging</title><link>/blog/2021/11/deep-dive-into-policy-logging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/11/deep-dive-into-policy-logging/</guid><description>Policies are regular programs. As such they often have the need to log information. In general, we are used to make our programs log into standard output (stdout) and standard error (stderr) outputs.
However, policies run in a confined WebAssembly environment. For this mechanism to work as usual Kubewarden would need to set up the runtime environment in a way that the policy can write to stdout and stderr file descriptors, and upon completion, Kubewarden can check them &amp;ndash; or stream log messages as they pop up.</description></item><item><title>A new architecture to ease Kubewarden administrators' lives</title><link>/blog/2021/10/new-architecture/new-architecture-to-ease-kubewarden-administrators-lives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/10/new-architecture/new-architecture-to-ease-kubewarden-administrators-lives/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce a new architecture for the Kubewarden stack, in line with its journey to maturity:
The introduction of a PolicyServer Custom Resource Definition (CRD) which allows users to describe a policy-server Deployment, together with binding ClusterAdmissionPolicies to a specific PolicyServer instance.
These 2 changes are accompanied by a multitude of improvements to make Kubewarden more comfortable for Kubernetes Administrators, such as validation for Kuberwarden Custom Resources, improvements in Helm Charts, Status and Conditions for ClusterAdmissionPolicies.</description></item><item><title>Towards a universal policy platform</title><link>/blog/2021/09/towards-a-universal-policy-platform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/09/towards-a-universal-policy-platform/</guid><description>Kubewarden is a policy framework for Kubernetes. It can be used to secure your clusters and to ensure they stay compliant with the rules your organization establishes over time.
By leveraging the power of WebAssembly, Kubewarden allows policy authors to write policies using traditional programming languages such as Rust, Go, AssemblyScript and Swift.
Kubewarden policies, once compiled into WebAssembly modules, are then distributed using regular OCI registries. This allows Operators to have a consistent way to securely distribute both container images and policies.</description></item><item><title>WebAssembly is coming to Cloud Native</title><link>/blog/2021/07/webassembly-is-coming-to-cloud-native/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/07/webassembly-is-coming-to-cloud-native/</guid><description>Is the title of this post a pun inspired by Christmas or by the Games of Thrones? I can&amp;rsquo;t decide&amp;hellip;
Are my dad jokes as bad as my daughters claim? Probably&amp;hellip;
Is WebAssembly spreading inside of the Cloud Native ecosystem? 💯 I have no doubts about that!
First of all, why am I so excited about seeing WebAssembly flourish inside of the Cloud Native ecosystem? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of it.</description></item><item><title>Let's learn Kubewarden - Streaming Event</title><link>/blog/2021/07/learn-kubewarden-streaming-event/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/07/learn-kubewarden-streaming-event/</guid><description>In case you missed, CNCF Ambassador Saiyam Pathak recently hosted a live streaming event on his YouTube channel about Kubewarden. Flavio had the pleasure to join Saiyam and give an overview of the project.
We spoke about Kubernetes Admission Controllers, why we started the Kubewarden project and how it differentiates from other existing open source projects such as Open Policy Agent and Kyverno.
The talk features also a brief overview of WebAssembly, what it is and what are the benefits it provides to Kubewarden.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the PSP host namespaces policy</title><link>/blog/2021/06/introducing-the-psp-host-namespaces-policy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/06/introducing-the-psp-host-namespaces-policy/</guid><description>As you probably know, Kubernetes Pod Security Policies (PSPs) are being deprecated in Kubernetes 1.21 &amp;ndash; although these APIs will be served until Kubernetes 1.25 it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to start thinking about what you will use to replace them.
At Kubewarden we have an ongoing effort to replace the Pod Security Policies with small, targeted Kubewarden policies.
Up until now, we have implemented some policies that replace some Pod Security Policies:</description></item><item><title>Introducing kwctl to Kubernetes Administrators</title><link>/blog/2021/06/kwctl-intro-for-kubernetes-administrators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/06/kwctl-intro-for-kubernetes-administrators/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce the availability of a new tool within the Kubewarden project: kwctl.
kwctl is a command line utility designed to help both policy authors and Kubernetes administrators.
This blog post focuses on the user experience of Kubernetes administrators. Future ones will cover the policy developer side of the story.
A Real-World Example: Controlling Container Capabilities The main character of today&amp;rsquo;s story is Alice. Alice is a Kubernetes administrator who wants to keep her Kubernetes cluster secure.</description></item><item><title>Writing your first policy with Kubewarden</title><link>/blog/2021/06/writing-your-first-policy-with-kubewarden/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/06/writing-your-first-policy-with-kubewarden/</guid><description>Kubewarden is a project focused on security and compliance. Its main goal is to allow you to write, test, distribute and run policies using the tooling that you already know and master, with a focus on controlling Kubernetes inner behaviors.
Policies are written in one of the supported languages, and the target object is a WebAssembly binary artifact. This is how Kubewarden can ensure that no matter where you built the policy, it can run on all platforms without any kind of adaptation.</description></item></channel></rss>